Hi, I'm Jason, previous Mac Genius, and today we're going to talk about how to switch users on a Mac.
And what we need to do to start this is to add a user, which is always a good idea for troubleshooting.
A lot of Geniuses will talk about this as a troubleshooting thing as well.
So we're going to go on to our system preferences.
We're going to click on accounts to make changes right here.
So I'm going to click on this and I'm going to put in the system admin password and that's going to unlock us.
And I want to add a user so I'm going to add Tim.
It's going to come up with the short name automatically, which you can change if you'd like to.
We're going to leave that and we're going to change Tim's password to Tim.
Verify that, Tim, and then we'll just say name and this can be anything you want.
We're going to create this account and we're going to turn automatic log in off.
This doesn't really matter.
You can change this setting later.
I'm going to turn it off.
And so now you can see here we've got Tim and Bing Hough.
And if you want to switch between these two what we need to do is click on the log in options here and enable fast user switching.
You're going to get this warning, this feature will allow other users to stay logged in and continue running software in the background while you're using this computer.
This is okay, like it says here, use this if you trust people, family members, things like that.
So I'm going to say okay.
Then, you'll notice up here, we've got these two log in screens there.
So I'm going to switch to Tim and it's going to ask us for Tim's password, which is Tim, and we're going to log in and you're going to get that beautifully revolving thing.
Hopefully, your screen catcher is still working and right now it's giving us basic systems for Tim.
And I'm going to go back up here, and go back to my original.
We're going to go back into Tim and what we need to do if we want to get rid of Tim's account is we need to log him out.
So the switch is over here, so here is Tim's screen and it gives you basically every sets on your system, preferences and everything like that for a new user.
And we're going to log Tim out because we want to throw, get rid of his account.
And so, we're going to log in here.
Okay.
Now we can select Tim and we can subtract him.
Delete immediately?
Yes.
And you can set parameters and parental controls for each of the accounts you have as well, so that's always a good thing to keep in mind if you've got younger children on the computer.
I'm Jason, previous Mac Genius, and I will speak with you later.
Bye.